Ankit Kumar Roshan

(akr.99799@gmail.com, +91 89497 05320)

Linkedin Github Portfolio

Overview

Passionate front-end developer with 2 years of industry experience specializing in building web applications. Involved in the core team, contributing to all phases of product development, including definition, design, scoping, planning, implementation, and testing of new features.

Work Experience

Appointy IT PVT LTD, Bhopal — Software Developer

August 2021 - PRESENT

Skills: Web Development, Reactjs, Typescript, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Graphql, React-relay, Material-UI, Team Management, Time Management

- Provide clean and efficient code review within the team.
- Collaborate with internal teams and vendors to enhance and fix product features, ensuring the best possible user experience.
- Work in an Agile-driven environment, effectively maintaining project timelines and utilizing available resources.
- Conduct research and optimize code to reduce application latency and enhance performance.
- An integral part of the core design and development team.
- Contribute to the development and delivery of multiple features to enterprise clients within specified time frames.
- Optimize web accessibility throughout the application.

Appointy IT PVT LTD, Bhopal — Software Developer Intern

May 2021 - July 2021

Skills: Reactjs, Typescript, GraphQl, Jest, Cypress.io

- Developed a feature that displays the respective location in search results and Google Maps when a customer searches for a zip code.
- Developed and optimized web components.
- Gained experience in unit testing and end-to-end testing of the application to measure its effectiveness.

Skills

- Reactjs
- TypeScript, JavaScript
- HTML, CSS
- GraphQL, React-relay
- Git
- Material-UI, Formik, Yup validation
- Jest, Cypress.io

Education

Vellore Institute Of Technology, Vellore — BTech

July 2017 - July 2021, Vellore

Electronic And Communication

CGPA: 7.8

Personal Work

• Covid tracker- Link